Stanley B. Symonds Papers VHP2006/1
CCSU Veterans History Project
Stanley B. Symonds Papers
1941 - 1945
VHP2006/1
CCSU Veterans History Project
281.0 Digital objects 4 Audio CD
This collection recounts the experiences of Stanley B. Symonds during his enlistment in World War II. The collection contains Stanley Symonds's memoirs which he recorded in 1981, personal service records, correspondence, and photographs. The correspondence chronicles Stanley Symonds relationships with fellow recruits and officers, his daily routines, trainings, and military deployments.
Symonds, Stanley B., 1920 - 2000
Biographical/Historical note
Stanley B. Symonds served as Signalman in the 41st Signal Company during World War II. A native of Stafford Springs, Connecticut, Technician Fifth Class Symonds served in Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, and Australia. He was the recipient of the Good Conduct Medal, the American Defense Service Medal, the Asiatic Pacific Theatre Campaign Ribbon, and the Philippine Liberation Ribbon with one Bronze Star.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
United States. Army. Signal Company, 41st.; United States. Army.; Australia; Manuscript; Papua New Guinea; Philippines; Photographs; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945 - - Papua, New Guinea; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/1.I
  - A book of transcribed letters written by Stanley Symonds to his family and Thelma Coker, his future wife, during his enlistment in World War II, Sept. 30, 1941 – Sept. 6, 1945; VHP2006/1.I.1; 270.0 Digital objects; Symonds, Stanley B., 1920 - 2000; Symonds, William
  - Honorable discharge certificate, 1945; VHP2006/1.I.2
  - Army Separation / Qualification record, 1945; VHP2006/1.I.3
  - Enlisted Record and Report of Separation, 1945; VHP2006/1.I.4
- Series II: Publications, VHP2006/1.II
  - Memoir of an Australian War Bride, n.d.; VHP2006/1.II.1; 2.0 Digital objects
- Series III: Multi-Media, VHP2006/1.III
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2006/1.III
    - Stanley B. Symonds military photo, Between 1941 - 1945; VHP2006/1.III.1
    - Thelma E. (Coker) Symonds and Stanley Symonds wedding portrait, St. Paul’s Cathedral, Rockhampton, Australia, Jan. 1, 1944; VHP2006/1.III.2
    - Stanley and Thelma with wedding attendants Thomas and Estelle MacClelland, St. Paul’s Cathedral, Rockhampton, Australia, Jan. 1, 1944; VHP2006/1.III.3
  - Subseries B: Audio, VHP2006/1.IIIb
    - Audio Memoir, January 5, 1981; VHP2006/1.IIIb.1 (Disk CD VHP2006/1, Box VHP Interview 2006)